### **SKILLS**

## Languages

Preferred: JS [ES6 and Typescript]

Known: Golang | C++

#### **General Skills**

Version Control | Basic Linux Environment | Classical and prototypal OOPs | Popular design patterns | Testing, debugging, linting, formatting and other dev practices

## Web Frontend Skills

HTML5 | CSS3 | ES6 | Typescript, babel, webpack and other modern toolchains | Modern styling paradigms | React.js Ecosystem | SSR | PWAs and web workers | Integration with various APIs including REST, GraphQL and gRPC architectures | Basic web assembly

### Web Backend Skills

Node.js and npm ecosystem | Data serialization formats (JSON & Protobuffers) | DBMS – SQL (MySQL) and NoSQL (MongoDB & Redis) | WebSocket and SSE | RESTful APIs | GraphQL APIs | gRPC APIs

#### **EDUCATION**

B. Tech, Computer Science and Engineering Maulana Azad National Institute of Technology, Bhopal CGPA: 8.98 July 2017 - July 2021

AISSCE, CBSE (12<sup>th</sup> grade) Sarvodaya Sr. Sec. School, Kota Percentage: 92% May 2016

## **CONTACT INFORMATION**

Mail: <a href="mailto:yashmahalwal@gmail.com">yashmahalwal@gmail.com</a>
Phone: +919521751778

#### YASH MAHALWAL

#### **SUMMARY**

A computer science undergrad with passion for bringing ideas to life. With 2+ years of experience in modern web development, has a broad technical skillset and can work with professional teams of all sizes to make production grade software.

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## Product development intern Appointy IT Pvt Ltd, Bhopal

May 2019 - April 2020

- Worked on the frontend team to make components of various scales and complexities for the product.
- Actively participated in architecture level planning for the frontend codebase. Also often debugged complicated bugs by combining knowledge of the product model and a deep understanding of technologies used.
- Participated in Appointy I/O. Wrote technical blogs and made numerous static pages

## **VOLUNTARY WORK**

# Head Web Developer ISTE Students' Chapter MANIT, Bhopal

May 2019 - Present

- Coordinated and mentored junior developers to create industry standard codebases. Responsible for code deployment.
- Designed and guided the implementation the platform for Megatreopuz 2019 an online cryptic hunt.

# Junior Web Developer ISTE Students' Chapter MANIT, Bhopal

May 2018 - May 2019

- Made numerous static and dynamic web apps using different tech stacks.
- Designed and implemented the platform for Megatreopuz 2018 an online cryptic hunt.

# **TOP PROJECTS**

#### Nirikshak - An autonomous API testing tool

An testing framework that uses the semantics of REST to generate test cases and analyze the data generated to provide meaningful insights. Aims to reduce human intervention to minimal.

# Megatreopuz 2019 - A online cryptic hunt platform

A complete platform to host the annual cryptic hunt for ISTE, MANIT. Highly scalable with focus on smooth user and developer experience along with performance and security.